Guide to the David Jacks Papers, 1845-1960
Department of Special Collections
David Jacks Papers,
1845-1960
Special Collections M068
David Jacks, 1822-1909
2.5 linear ft.
Stanford University. Libraries. Dept. of Special Collections and University Archives.
Administrative Information
Access Restrictions:
None.
Provenance:
Gift of the Jacks family, 1945, and of Norman Earl, July 1966.
BIOGRAPHY
David Jacks was born in 1822 in the village of Crieff in Perthshire, Scotland. In 1841 he followed two older brothers across the Atlantic. He was a clerk, for a short time, at Williamsburg, N.Y., and in the mid 1840s, was a wheelwright at Ft. Hamilton, N.Y. In 1848 news of the discovery of gold in California reached the East Coast. Young Jacks became an accountant for a sutler attached to the 3rd Regiment of Artillery. This outfit left New York in November or December of 1848, went around the Horn and landed in San Francisco in April of 1849. Jacks spent the remainder of that year working at the Presidio and became naturalized as U. S. citizen in December.
In January 1850, the steamer "California" carried David Jacks to Monterey. He worked for a short time for a merchant, Joseph Boston, and then became a clerk for James McKinlay who ran a grocery and dry goods store. McKinlay was also interested in real estate and loans. In the winter of 1851, McKinlay took a trip to San Francisco, leaving Jacks to handle the store and his various business interests. Loaning of money and acquiring land became very important in Jacks' life, making him the largest landowner and richest citizen of Monterey County.
David Jacks married Maria Christina de la Soledad Romie on April 20, 1861. They had seven children. Mrs. Jacks, the daughter of German immigrants, was born in Mexico. Her parents, Juan Federico and Maria Frohn Romie moved to Monterey where they held quite a bit of land. One of the Romie properties was the Rancho El Pescadero which later belonged to Jacks. Mary's three brothers also helped Jacks run and manage his constantly increasing holdings.
Jacks' whole life and career in Monterey was marked by an almost constant series of lawsuits both by and against him. Most of them concerned conflicting property and boundary claims. He had two lawyers in Washington, D.C. handling his claims before the Supreme Court, and numerous others in California. In l868, Jacks bought D.R. Ashley's share in the Monterey Pueblo Lands. He thus became sole owner of property that was to cause him a good deal of trouble. In 1877, the City of Monterey brought the initial suit for fraud to try to recover the land. Litigations continued until 1903 when the courts finally ruled in favor of Jacks.
David Jacks was also one of the builders of Monterey County. He was instrumental in the construction of the narrow gauge Monterey & Salinas Valley railroad in 1874, and in its sale to the Southern Pacific in 1879. In 1875, he donated a large amount of land for the founding of Pacific Grove as a religious resort. He also helped to found the community of Del Monte. He donated funds for organizational and individual charities. He helped support churches, ministers, and missionaries of almost any Protestant denomination that seemed to need it. Jacks was also active in the field of education. This included financial support of the Monterey County public schools, and service as a member of the Board of Trustees of the University of the Pacific. He so impressed his children with the importance of education that many years after his death in 1909, his family contributed handsomely to Stanford University in land and other securities. Part of these funds endowed two professorships in education.
SCOPE AND CONTENT
The DAVID JACKS PAPERS include correspondence, primarily business; legal and official documents in the form of leases, bills of sale, transfers of title, and court actions; financial papers; maps; clippings and printed materials; and photographs, photostats and prints. There are also some notes from various sources and interviews which Arthur E. Bestor, Jr. made in connection with his biography of David and Lee L. Jacks. This was printed in a limited edition by Stanford University in 1945.
The Jacks material is dated between 1845 and 1905 with the bulk falling in the 1860s. The largest single subject is Jacks' personal business. In this category, as in all those in this collection, the legal and financial papers are equally as important as the correspondence. The business material pertains to the management of Jacks' properties, the shipping and sale of produce and livestock locally, and in San Francisco and Los Angeles, and the purchase of needed material and equipment.
Because of the seemingly endless law suits in which he was involved, there are a great number of legal documents and records and a lot of correspondence with lawyers. Most of it is related to land questions. The two most important are the Monterey Pueblo Lands case and the claims regarding the Rancho Chualar before the Supreme Court in Washington, D.C. A very interesting case not pertaining to land is that with H.H. Bancroft's The History Company over an article and etching of Jacks for The Chronicle of Kings.
The financial papers are full of drafts and cancelled notes. The former show some of Jacks' activity as a business agent for persons such as D.R. Ashley, and his charity in California and in Scotland. The cancelled give some idea of the scope of his loan activities.
The collection also includes several folders containing papers of Margaret Jacks and other family members, dating between 1895 and 1960.
CONTAINER LIST
- CORRESPONDENCE 1850-52 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - 1. Brown, Geo[rge] to John Morrison, Sept. 24, 1850., 4 pp.
  - 2. Hamilton J[ohn] to John Morrison, Mar. 1 1851., 3 pp.
  - 3. Tierney, E. P. to John Morrison, Apr. 4, 1851., 4 pp.
  - 4. Parker, E. M. to David Jack[s], Apr. 21, 1851., 1 p.
  - 5. McKinlay, Ja[me]s to David Jacks, Dec. 13, 1851., 2 pp.
  - 6. McKinlay, Ja[me]s to David Jacks, Dec. 24, 1851., 2 pp.
  - 7. McKinlay, Ja[me]s to David Jacks, Feb. 10, 1852., 2 pp.
  - 8. McKinlay, Ja[me]s to David Jacks, Feb. 10, 1852., 2 pp.
  - 9. Jacks, D[avid] to James McKinlay, Feb.18, 1852., 4 pp.
  - 10. McKinlay, Ja[me]s to David Jacks, Feb. 23, 1852., 2 pp.
  - 11. McKinlay, Ja[me]s to David Jacks, Mar. 3, 1852., 2 pp.
  - 12. McKinlay, Ja[me]s to David Jacks, Mar. 27, 1852., 1 p.
  - 13. McKinlay, Ja[me]s to David Jacks, Apr. 3, 1852., 2 p
  - 14. [Kendall],A. to David Jacks, Jul. 8, 1852., 4 pp.
  - 15. Wallace, William T. to David Jacks, Aug. 20, 1852., 1 p. & cvr.
  - 15a. Brown, George to John Morrison, Sept. 26, 1852., 4pp.
  - 16. Ashley, D[elos] R[odeyn] to [David] Jacks, Dec. 8, 1852., 1 p.
- CORRESPONDENCE 1853-54 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - 1. Harkinson, Caroline [C.] to [John Morrison], [Jun. 26, 1853].4 pp. fragment; Oct. 26, [1853].4pp.; Jan. 8, 1854.4pp.
  - 2. Russell, W. G. to Unknown. Jan. 12, 1854., 2 pp.
  - 3. Touchstone, [Nancy] Jane (Mrs. John B.) to Unknown. Feb. 1, 1854., 2 pp.
- CORRESPONDENCE 1856, 1858 and 1859 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - 1. Keating, John to M[atthew] C. Ireland, Jan. 3, 1856., l pp. jury summons, printed
  - 2. Curtis & Conover to John [B.] Touchstone, Apr. 5, 1856., 1 p.
  - 3. Jacks, David to Unknown (Editor of Christian Intelligencer of New York), Jun. 17, 1856., 1 p.
  - 4. Hardy, Alpheus & Co. to Lewis Gibson, Nov. 7, 1856., 2 pp.
  - 5. [Jones, J.] to David Jacks, Feb. 8, 1858., 1 p.
  - 6. Brennan & Co. to M[atthew] C. Ireland, Mar. 24, 1858., 1 p. price list, ptd.
  - 7. Tierney, E. P. to John Morrison, Sept. 15, 1858., 3 pp.
  - 8. Haight, F[letcherl M. to David Jacks, Mar. 19, 1859., 3pp.
  - 9. Haight, F[letcherl M. to David Jacks, Apr. 21, 1859., 3 pp.
  - 10. Malarin, Mariano to Unknown, May 2, 1859., 2 pp.
  - 11. Haight, F[letcher] M. to David Jacks, Aug. 16, 1859., 2 pp.
  - 12. Hally, W[illia]m to David Jacks, Aug. 25, 1859., 4 pp. & cvr.
  - 13. Taylor, Alex[ander] S. to David Jacks, Aug. 31, 1859., 3 pp.
  - 14. Rayle, R.M.S. to F.M. & H.H. Haight, Oct. 5. 1859., 2 pp.
  - 15. Jacks, C[hristian] to [David Jacks], Oct. 20, 1859., 6 pp. & cvr.
  - 16. Stramler, William A. to Lewis [Little], Nov. 20, 1859., 3 pp.
  - 17. Lane, J.[P.] to David Jacks, Dec. 30, 1859., 1 p.
- CORRESPONDENCE 1860 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - 1. Scrimgeour, W[illiam] Jr. to Unknown, Jan. 19, 1860.(probably to Jacks), 4 pp.
  - 2. Jacks, Christian to David Jacks, Feb. 15, 1860., 8 pp. & cvr.
  - 3. Lane J.P. to David Jacks, Mar. 19, 1860., 3 pp. & cvr.
  - 4. Jack[s], Christian to David Jacks, Jul. 19, 1860., 4 pp. & cvr.
  - 5. Jacks, David to Mary C. Romia (later Mrs. Jacks), Jul. 23, 1860., 2 pp.
  - 6. Conway, Edward to David Jacks, Jul. 25, 1860., 2 pp.
  - 7. Robert, T. S., Aug. 17, 1860 -Monterey Co. real & personal property tax rate, certified copy, 1 p.
  - 8. Leese, J[acob]- P[rimer] to Alexander S. Taylor, Aug. 23, 1860., 2 pp.
  - 9. Agustin, Antonio, Dec. 31, 1860.List of household goods, 3 pp.
  - 10. Ashley, D[elos] R[odeyn] [1860].Blank notice to trespassers. (by David Jacks also)., 1 pp.
  - 11.& 12. Ashley, D[elos] R[odeyn] [1860].Blank notice to trespassers., 3 pp.
- CORRESPONDENCE 1861 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - 1. Jacks, Christian to [David Jacks], Feb. 14, 1861., 6 pp.
  - 2. Laurie, John to [David] Jacks, Feb. 19, 1861., 3 pp.
  - 3. Fox, Bernard S. to David Jacks, Mar. 12, 1861., 1 p.
  - 4. [Arceo Doña R.] to [____ Aulel] Mar. 21, 1861., 2 pp. in Spanish.
  - 5. Walker, Andrew (of Rowland & Walker) to David Jacks. Apr. 20, 1861., 2 pp. with bill.
  - 6. Loud, John M. to D[avid] Jacks, Apr. 23, 1861., 2 pp.
  - 7. Slocum W[illia]m N. to Unknown, Apr. 23, 1861., 3 pp.
  - 8. Coles, Henry to [David] Jacks, May 20, 1861., 2 pp.
  - 9. Burns, Uriah to Daniel Harris, Jun. 22, 1861.Appointment with Harris' oath of office on verso., 2 pp.
  - 10.[Augistin], Antonio to [David] Jacks, Jul. 5, 1861., 3 pp.
  - 11. Mitchinson, George to Walter Langton. Jul. 11, 1861.
  - 12. Munson, John to [David] Jacks, Jul. 15, 1861., 2 pp.
  - 13. Wilkinson, Peter to [David] Jacks, Jul. 24, 1861., 2 pp.
  - 14. McMahon, James to David Jacks, Jul. 29, 1861., 2 pp.
  - 15. Briggs, M.C. to David Jacks, Aug. 9, 1861., 3 pp.
  - 16. O'Brien, W. S. to [David] Jacks, Aug. 12, 1861., 1 p.
  - 17. Jacks, David to James McMahon, Aug. 16, 1861.with receipt Daniel O'Callaghan to DJ same date., 2 pp.
  - 18. Flood, J[ames] C[laire] to David Jacks, Nov. 15, 1861., 2 pp.
  - 19. Woodworth, Fred[rick] A. to David Jacks, Nov. 22, 1861., 2 pp.
  - 20. Rogers, James to D[avid] Jacks, Nov. 29, 1861., 4 pp.
  - 21. Cushing, A. C. to David Jacks, Dec. 14, 1861., 2 pp.
  - 22. Stinson, J. B. to [David] Jacks, Dec. 20, 1861., 2 pp.
- CORRESPONDENCE 1862 Jan.-Jun. (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - 1. Weed, Joseph & W[illia]m Hollis, Jan. 1 1862.Ptd. announcement from Grand Division [Sons of Temperance] State of California., 2pp.
  - 2. Flood [James Claire] to David Jacks, Jan. 16, 1862., 2 pp.
  - 3. Ashley, [Delos R.] to [David] Jacks, Jan. 19, 1862., 2 pp.
  - 4. Hartman, Isaac to David Jacks, Feb. 14, 1862., 3 pp.
  - 5. Hollis, [William] to David Jacks, Feb. 17, 1862., 3 pp.
  - 6. McMahon, James to David Jacks, Feb. 25, 1862., 2 pp.
  - 7. Romie, Charles T. to [David] Jacks, Feb. 27, 1862.
  - 8. Rowland & Walker to David Jacks, Feb. 27, 1862., 2 pp.
  - 9. Hally [William] to David Jacks, Mar. 1, 1862., 2 pp.
  - 10. Weed, Joseph to David Jacks, Mar. 17, 1862., 2 pp. ptd. appointment
  - ll. Callaghan, [John] D. to [David] Jacks, Mar. 25, 1862., 4 pp.
  - 12. Boston, Joseph to David Jacks, Apr. 1, 1862., 2 pp. Tel.
  - 13. Rowland & Walker to David Jacks, Apr. 22, 1862., 2 pp.
  - 14. Flood, [James C.] to David Jacks, May 5, 1862., 2 pp.
  - 15. Ashley, [Delos R.] to [David] Jacks, May 12, 1862., 2 pp.
  - 16. Romie, Ernest to David Jacks, May 27, 1862., 3 pp.
  - 17. Hartman, [Isaac] to David Jacks, May 30, 1862., 2 pp.
  - 18. Romie, E[rnest] to David Jacks, Jun. 7, 1862., 3 pp.
  - 19. Dennis, Tho[mas] to David Jacks, Jun. 13, 1862., 2 pp.
  - 20. Romie, Ernest to Unknown, Jun. 18, 1862., 4 pp. in Spanish.
  - 21. Walker, Andrew to [David] Jacks, Jun. 18, 1862., 2 pp.
  - 22. Dennis, Tho[mas] to David Jacks, Jun. 27, 1862., 2 pp.
  - 23. Harrison, Ralph C. to [David] Jacks, Jun. 30, 1862., 2 pp.
- CORRESPONDENCE 1862 Jul.-Dec. (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - 1. Cox, Clement to David Jacks, Jul. 1, 1862., 2 pp.
  - 2. McElroy, [James R.] to David Jacks, Jul. 1, 1862., 2 pp.
  - 3. Slocum W[illiam] N. to David Jacks, Jul. 1, 1862., 4 pp.
  - 4. Flood J[ames] C[laire] to David Jacks, Jul. 3, 1862., 2 pp.
  - 5. Wheeler, John [O.] to D[avid] Jacks, Jul. 7, 1862., 2 pp.
  - 6. Dennis, [Thomas] to David Jacks, Jul. 18, 1862., 2 pp.
  - 7. Romie, C[harles] [T.] to [David] Jacks, Jul. 22, 1862., 4 pp.
  - 8. Bannister, E. G. to David Jacks, J ul. 25, 1862., 2 pp.
  - 9. Barrows, H.D. to David Jacks, Jul. 28, 1862., 2 pp.
  - 10. Gitchell, J.R. to D[avid] Jacks, Jul. 28, 1862., 2 pp.
  - 11. Briggs, M.C. to David Jacks, Aug. 1, 1862., 2 pp.
  - 12. McLean, John T. to [David] Jacks, Aug. 1, 1862., 2 pp.
  - 13. Thorn Thomas to David Jacks, Aug. 3, 1862., 2 pp.
  - 14. Ashley, [Delos R.] to [David] Jacks, Aug. 28, 1862., 2 pp.
  - 15. Flood & O'Brien to David Jacks, Aug. 11, 1862., 2 pp.
  - 16. McElroy, Robert to [David] Jacks, Aug. 22, 1862., 2 pp.
  - 17. Gulick, L[uther] H[alsey Sr.] to David Jacks, Sept. 1. 1862., 4 pp.
  - 18. [Maclay] C. to David Jacks, Sept. 8, 1862., 2 pp.
  - 19. Murdock, F.B. to David Jacks, Sept. 8, 1962., 2 pp.
  - 20. Murdock, F.B. to C[harles] Maclay, Sept. 8, 1862., 2 pp.
  - 21. Flood, J[ames] C. to David Jacks, Sept. 16, 1862., 2 pp.
  - 22. Gafney, William to D[avid] Jacks, Sept. 23, 1862., 2 pp.
  - 23. Walker, Andrew to David Jacks, Sept. 23, 1862., 2 pp.
  - 24. Hollis, William to David Jacks, Sept. 30, 1862.Ptd. announcement., 2 pp.
  - 25. Smith, S. Wilson T. to David Jacks, Oct. 22, 1862., 2 pp.
  - 26. Smith, S. Wilson T. to David Jacks, Oct. 28, 1862., 2 pp.
  - 27. Rowland & Walker to David Jacks, Oct. 28, 1862., 2 pp.
  - 28. Groves, A. W. to [David] Jacks, Oct. 28, 1862., 2 pp.
  - 29. Haight, F[letcher] M. to David Jacks, Oct. 29, 1862., 2 pp.
  - 30. Dogwood, Thomas Y. to David Jacks, Oct., 1862., 2 pp.
  - 31. Syme, William Sr. to D[avid] Jacks, Oct., 1862., 4 pp.
  - 32. Smith, S. Wilson T. to David Jacks, Nov. 7, 1862., 2 pp.
  - 33. McElroy, J[ames R.] to David Jacks, Nov. l2, 1862., 2 pp.
  - 34. Lemmons, James to (David) Jacks, Nov. 28, 1862., 2 pp.
  - 35. Brown, Theodore to [David] Jacks, Nov. 30, 1862., 2 pp.
  - 36. Swan, Douglas to David Jacks, Dec. 8, 1862., 2 pp.
  - 37. Cobb, James C. to David Jacks, Dec. 9, 1862., 2 pp.
  - 38. Wallace, W. T. to David Jacks, Dec. 9, 1862., 2 pp.
  - 39. Hardy, Alpheus & Co. to John B.R. Cooper, Dec. 10, 1862., 2 pp.
  - 40. Byrne, James & Michael Meagher to [David] Jacks, Dec. 15, 1862., 2 pp.
  - 41. Wickes, James E. to [David] Jacks, Dec. 22, 1862., 2 pp.
  - 42. Ashley, D.R. & David Jacks, [1862].trespass notice., 2pp.
  - 43. Unknown to John Morrison, [1862 or 1863?].Inked inscription: Juana Simbreros., lp. & cvr.
- CORRESPONDENCE 1863 Jan.-Apr. (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - 1. Temperance petition. Jan. 1, 1863., 2 pp. ptd., not signed
  - 2. Dogwood, Thomas Y. to David Jacks, Jan. 1, 1863., 2 pp.
  - 3. Tuthill, D. to David Jacks, Jan. 1, 1863., 2 pp.
  - 4. Potter, A.P. to Unknown, Jan. 4, 1863., 2 pp.
  - 5. Romie, [Ernest] to David Jacks, Jan. 10, 1863., 2 pp.
  - 6. Gafney, William to David Jacks, Jan. 12, 1863., 4 pp.
  - 7. Rowland & Walker to David Jacks, Jan. 23, 1863., 2 pp.
  - 8. Romie, E[rnest] to David Jacks, Feb. 7, 1863., 2 pp.
  - 9. Albert, Ed. to David Jacks, Feb. 13, 1863., 3 pp.
  - 10. Ashley & Jacks to Pedro L. Gonzales, trespass notice. Feb. 12, 1863., 2 pp.
  - 11. Ashley & Jacks, blank trespass notice. Feb. 13, 1863., 2 pp.
  - 12. Hardy, Alpheus Co. to John B.R. Cooper, Feb. 14, 1863., 3 pp.
  - 13. Cool, P.Y. to David Jacks, Feb. 23, 1863., 2 pp.
  - 14. Ashley, Annie to [David] Jacks, Mar. 1, 1863., 3 pp.
  - 15. Rowland & Walker to David Jacks, Mar. 1, 1863., 2 pp.
  - 16. Briggs, M.C. to David Jacks, Mar. 2, 1863., 2 pp.
  - 17. McCrea, Tho[mas] to D[avid] Jacks, Mar. 2, 1863., 2 pp.
  - 18. Coles, Henry to (David) Jacks, Mar. 4, 1863., 2 pp. & dkt
  - 19. Taylor, Alex[ander] S. to David Jacks, Mar. 14, 1863., 6 pp.
  - 20. Davidson James [A.] to David Jacks, Mar. 31, 1863., 4 pp.
  - 21. Romie, Charles [T.] to [David] Jacks, Apr. 17, 1863., 2 pp.
  - 22. Tuthill, D. to David Jacks, Apr. 17, 1863., 3 pp.
  - 23. Rowland & Walker, to David Jacks, Apr. 23, 1863., 2 pp. Tel.
  - 24. Romie, E[rnest] to David Jacks, Apr. 25, 1863., 2 pp. Tel.
  - 25. Tompkins, Edward to D[avid] Jacks, Apr. 28, 1863., 2 pp.
- CORRESPONDENCE 1863 May-Sept. (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - 1. Romie, Cha[rles] T. to D[avid] Jacks, May 9, 1863., 3 pp.
  - 2. Tompkins, Edward to D[avid] Jacks, May 11, 1863., 3 pp.
  - 3. Rowland & Walker to D. Jacks, May 14, 1863., 2 pp.
  - 4. Moore, G.E. to Rowland & Walker, assay report. May 16, 1863., 2 pp.
  - 5. Ohm, [Fritz] to Unknown, May 18, 1863., 2 pp. in German
  - 6. Rowland & Walker to David Jacks, May 19, 1863., 2 pp. Tel.
  - 7. Davidson, James A. to D[avid] Jacks, May 20, 1863., 2 pp.
  - 8. Rowland & Walker to D. Jacks, May 23, 1863., 2 pp.
  - 9. Davidson, James A. to D. Jacks, May 27, 1863., 2 pp.
  - 10. Headen, B. [Y. or F.] to Unknown, May 29, 1863., 2 pp.
  - 11. Higgins, E. to D. Jacks, May 29, 1863.
  - 12. Rowland & Walker to D. Jacks, May 29, 1863., 2 pp.
  - 13. Josselyn, E.P. to D. Jacks Jun. 2, 1863., 2 pp. Tel.
  - 14. McCrea, Thomas to Unknown, Jun. 2, 1863., 2 pp.
  - 15. Rowland & Walker to D. Jacks, Jun. 9, 1863., 2 pp.
  - 16. Lyons, A. to D. Jacks, Jun. 15, 1863., 2 pp.
  - 17. Olinger, A.F. to D. Jacks, Jun. 16, 1863., 3 pp.
  - 18. Romie, C[harles] T. to Maria. F. Romie, Jun. 17, 1863., 2 pp. in Spanish.
  - 19. Rowland & Walker to D. Jacks, Jun. 18, 1863., 2 pp.
  - 20. Rowland & Walker to D. Jacks, Jun. 26, 1863., 2 pp.
  - 21. Briggs, M.C. to D. Jacks, Jun. 27, 1863., 2 pp. Tel.
  - 22. Higgins, E. to D. Jacks, Jul. 6. 1863., 2 pp.
  - 23. Emery, J.S. to D. Jacks, Jul. 20, 1863., 2 pp.
  - 24. Taylor, John to D. Jacks, Jul. 31, 1863., 2 pp.
  - 25. Flood, James C. to D. Jacks, Aug. 27, 1863., 2 pp.
  - 26. Boston Joseph to D. Jacks, Aug. 28. 1863., 2 pp.
  - 27. Cool, P. Y. to D. Jacks, Aug. 29, 1863., 2 pp.
  - 28. Hooper, W[illia]m to D. Jacks, Sept. 1, 1863., 2 pp.
  - 29. Jacks, David to Paul Romie, Sept. 3, 1863., 2 pp.
  - 30. Rims, Warren to D. Jacks, Sept. 11, 1863., 4 pp.
  - 31. Leese J[acob] P. to D. Jacks, Sept. 14, 1863., 2 pp.
  - 32. McCobb., Henry D. to D. Jacks, Sept. 14, 1863., 2 pp.
  - 33. Cool, P. Y. to D. Jacks, Sept. 16, 1863., 2 pp.
  - 34. Leese, J[acob] P. to D. Jacks, Sept. 22, 1863., 2 pp.
  - 35. Rowland & Walker to D. Jacks, Sept. 22, 1863., 2 pp.
  - 36. McCobb, Henry D. to D. Jacks, Sept. 28, 1863., 2 pp.
  - 37. Nims, Warren to D. Jacks, Sept. 28, 1863., 2 pp.
- CORRESPONDENCE 1863 Oct.-Dec. (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - 1. Jacks, David to Ernest Romie, Oct. 1, 1863., 2 pp.
  - 2. Slocum, W[illiam] M. to D. Jacks, Oct. 6. 1863., 4 pp.
  - 3. Jacks, David to E. Romie, Oct. 7, 1863., 2 pp.
  - 4. Ashley, [Delos R.] to D. Jacks, Oct. 10, 1863., 2 pp.
  - 5. Chase, B. F. to DJ, Oct. 10, 1863., 3 pp.
  - 6. Rowland & Walker to D. Jacks, Oct 17, 1863., 2 pp.
  - 7. Byrne, M. J. to John Rudle, Oct. 19, 1863., 2 pp.
  - 8. Jones, J. to DJ, Oct. 20, 1863., 2 pp. Tel.
  - 9. Stow, W. [N.] to DJ, Oct. 20, 1863., 2 pp.
  - 10. Banning, Phineas to DJ, Oct. 23, 1863., 2 pp.
  - 11. Clark & Perkins to DJ, Oct. 26, 1863., 2 pp.
  - 12. Beals, John P. to DJ, Oct. 27, 1863., 3 pp.
  - 13. Dogwood, Thomas Y. to DJ, Oct. 31, 1863., 2 pp.
  - 14. Kirby, R.C. to DJ, Oct. 31, 1863., 2 pp.
  - 15. Phillips John Burke to DJ, Oct. 31, 1863., 2 pp.
  - 16. Patton, [G.] A. to E[rnest] Romie, Oct. 31, 1863., 2 pp.
  - 17. Romie, E[rnest] to (Paul Romie], Nov. 12, 1863., 2 pp. in Spanish.
  - 18. Jacks, M[ary] C. to DJ, Nov. 15, 1863., 3 pp.
  - 19. Romie, Ernest to DJ, Nov. 17, 1863., 3 pp.
  - 20. Bichard, Nicholas to DJ, Nov. 19, 1863., 2 pp.
  - 21. Thompson, John to DJ, Nov. 23, 1863., 2 pp.
  - 22. Romie, Ernest to DJ, Nov. 29, 1863., 4 pp.
  - 23. Ashley, Annie to DJ, Nov. 30, 1863., 4 pp.
  - 24. Pollock, _____ to Rowland, Walker & Co., Dec. 1, 1863., 2 pp. Tel.
  - 25. Hartman, Isaac to DJ, Dec. 7, 1863., 3 pp.
  - 26. Flood & O'Brien to DJ, Dec. 8, 1863., 2 pp.
  - 27. McDonald, Narbonne P. to Rowland, Walker & Co., Dec. 10, 1863., 2 pp.
  - 28. Flood & O'Brien to DJ, Dec. 11, 1863., 2 pp.
  - 29. Coles, Henry to DJ, Dec. 13, 1863., 3 pp.
  - 30. Fox, Charles N. to DJ, Dec. 17, 1863., 2 pp. Ptd. appointment.
  - 31. Rowland, Walker & Co. to DJ, Dec. 17, 1863., 2 pp.
  - 32. Boston, Joseph to DJ, Dec. 18, 1863., 2 pp.
  - 33. Gulick, L.H. to DJ, Dec. 18, 1863. (Luther Halsey, Sr.), 4 pp.
  - 34. Rowland Walker & Co. to DJ, Dec. 22, 1863., 2 pp.
  - 35. Josselyn, A.S. to DJ, Dec. 30, 1863., 2 pp.
  - 36. Geil, S.F. to Eugenio Martinez, [1863]., 3 pp. 2 same date.
  - 37. Geil, S.F. to Gracia Martinez & Francisco Alvitre, [1863]., 2 pp. 2 same date.
  - 38. Ashley & Jacks, blank trespass notice. [1863]., 1 p.
- CORRESPONDENCE 1864, Jan.-Mar. (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - 1. Ord, J[ames] L. to DJ, Jan. 1, 1864., 2 pp.
  - 2. Taylor, Geo[rge] B. to DJ, Jan. 3, 1864., 3 pp.
  - 3. Romie, C[harles] T. to Ernest [Romie], Jan. 4, 1864., 1 p. in Spanish.
  - 4. Banning, Phineas to DJ, Jan. 6. 1864., 2 pp.
  - 5. [Kirby,] R.C. to DJ, Jan. 6, 1864., 2 pp.
  - 6. Rowland Walker & Co. to DJ, Jan. 6, 1864., 2 pp.
  - 7. Taylor, John to DJ, Jan. 6, 1864., 2 pp.
  - 8. Rowland Walker & Co. to DJ, Jan. 7, 1864., 2 pp.
  - 9. Brown, Theodore to DJ, Jan. 12, 1864., 2 pp.
  - 10. Taylor, John to DJ, Jan. 19, 1864., 2 pp.
  - 11. Bannister, E. to DJ, Jan. 29, 1864., 4 pp.
  - 12. Lynch, S.Q. to DJ, Jan. 29, 1864., 2 pp.
  - 13. Hill, John B. to DJ, Feb. 1, 1864., 2 pp.
  - 14. Hopkins, [Theron R.] to DJ, Feb. 1, 1864., 2 pp.
  - 15. Craig, A. to Phineas Banning, Feb. 2, 1864., 2 pp.
  - 16. Rowland Walker & Co. to DJ, Feb. 8, 1864., 2 pp.
  - 17. Martin, W.H. to DJ, Feb. 10, 1864., 2 pp.
  - 18. Rowland Walker & Co. to DJ, Feb. 11, 1864., 2 pp.
  - 19. Taylor, John to DJ, Feb. 11, 1864., 2 pp.
  - 20. Banning, Phineas to DJ, Feb. 12, 1864., 2 pp.
  - 21. Pool, J.B. to DJ, Feb. 13, 1864., 2 pp.
  - 22. Sutton, James L. to Unknown (John), Feb. 18, 1864.Sight draft to DJ, witnessed by J.D. Callaghan., 2 pp.
  - 23. Allen & Spier to DJ, Feb. 20, 1864., 2 pp.
  - 24. Sherwood, Eugene to DJ, Feb. 20, 1864., 2 pp.
  - 25. Jacks, David to Phineas Banning, Feb. 25, 1864., 2 pp.
  - 26. Taylor, John to DJ, Mar. 1, 1864., 2 pp. Tel.
  - 27. Craig, A. to DJ, Mar. 3, 1864., 2 pp.
  - 28. Rich, Charles E. to DJ, Mar. 3, 1864., 2 pp.
  - 29. Rowland Walker & Co. to DJ, Mar. 5, 1864., 2 pp. & clip.
  - 30. Crawford, A. & Co. to DJ, Mar. 9, 1864., 2 pp.
  - 31. Flood & O'Brien to DJ, Mar. 12, 1864., 2 pp.
  - 32. Romie, E[rnest] to DJ, Mar. 14, 1864., 2 pp. Tel.
  - 33. Cooper, John B.R. to DJ, Mar. 15, l864., 2 pp.
  - 34. Jacks, David to E[rnest] Romie, Mar. 15, 1864., 2 pp. Tel.
  - 35. Romie, Ernest to DJ, Mar. 15, 1864., 3 pp.
  - 36. Cooper, J[ohn] B.R. to DJ, Mar. 16, 1864., 2 pp. Tel.
  - 37. Cooper, J[ohn] B.R. to DJ Mar. 17, 1864., 2 pp. Tel.
  - 38. Hartman, Isaac to DJ Mar. 17, 1864., 3 pp.
  - 39. Higbie, A. to DJ, Mar. 17, 1864., 2 pp.
  - 40. Owen, J.J. to DJ, Mar. 17, 1864., 2 pp.
  - 41. Unknown to E. Higgins, Mar. 18, 1864., 2 pp.
  - 42. Woolley, John C. to DJ, Mar. 21, 1864., 2 pp.
  - 43. Ashley, Annie to DJ, Mar. 26, 1864., 3 pp.
  - 44. Higgins, E. to DJ, Mar. 26, 1864., 2 pp.
  - 45. Tuthill, D. (David) to DJ, Mar. 26, 1864., 4 pp.
  - 46. Hartman, Isaac to DJ, Mar. 28, 1864., 2 pp.